welcome to another darktable tutorial in
欢迎来到中的另一个暗表教程
this video we'll be doing the color
这个视频我们要做的是颜色
zones module and learning how to use it
Zones模块和学习如何使用它
color zones you can find it down here
颜色区域你可以在这里找到它
under more modules this is an
在更多模块下 这是一个
alphabetical order just go down to color
按字母顺序排列就是颜色
zones and then we'll just click it and
区域 然后我们只需点击它
make sure that appears and that's how we
确保这一点出现 这就是我们
got this effect here so what we did we
在这里得到了这种效果 所以我们所做的是
took our original image or our base
把我们的原始形象或我们的基地
image and then we just adjusted the
图像 然后我们只需调整
color so we've got some more pink and
所以我们有更多的粉色和
purple instead of what the original was
紫色而不是原来的样子
with like this red paint you can
像这样的红色油漆 你可以
download this image from we saturate on
从我们饱和的网站下载这张图片
through the link in the description this
通过描述中的链接
video if you want to follow along
如果您想要跟随 请观看视频
there's a really good image for using
有一个非常好的图像可以使用
this tool so the color zones when we
这个工具让我们在色带的时候
select it we have some different options
选择它 我们有一些不同的选择
we have it shows us a bunch of little
我们有它向我们展示了一堆
colored boxes and when we hover our
彩色盒子和当我们在我们的
mouse over it does this sort of weird
鼠标悬停在上面会让人觉得很奇怪
squiggly type thing we can adjust the
弯曲型的东西我们可以调整
size and the influence of it with our
大小及其对我们的影响
scroll wheel and then we have lightness
滚动滚轮 然后我们就有了轻盈
saturation and the chart kind of changes
饱和度和图表类型的变化
for saturation and we have hue and the
对于饱和度 我们有色调和
chart will change for that as well well
图表也会因此而改变
the what I did for to create that look
我所做的一切都是为了创造这样的形象
let's just go back and go to compress
我们还是回去按压吧
history stack so this is kind of back to
历史堆栈 所以这有点回到
the base now what I first did I went to
基地现在我做的第一件事是我去了
hue and we selected by hue well actually
色调和我们实际上按色调很好地选择了
let's start with the beginning
让我们从头开始吧
lightness so we can select certain
亮度 所以我们可以选择某些
colors certain pixel color groups within
为其中的某些像素颜色组上色
this image and adjust the lightness of
此图像并调整其亮度
just those colors so to do this we can
只有那些颜色 所以要做到这一点 我们可以
need to look on the chart and
需要查看图表 然后
approximate with our eye or we can click
用我们的眼睛近似 或者我们可以点击
and get the color picker here and we can
把选色器放在这里 我们就可以
drag this around to a certain point so
把它拖到某个点上 这样
if we drag it to these yellows it draws
如果我们把它拖到这些黄色 它就会画出来
a an indicator to see that there's like
一个指示器 可以看到有像这样的
a black line now that wasn't there
一条不存在的黑线
before
在此之前
in right in the middle of these yellows
就在这些黄色的中间
and so that shows us where that kind of
这就向我们展示了这种
falls the zone that these colors are in
落在这些颜色所在的区域
and then we can just left click on these
然后我们只需左键点击这些
and we can increase the lightness or the
我们可以增加亮度或
darkness of just those colors let's zoom
就是那些颜色的黑暗让我们变焦
out I'm hitting the control wheel on my
在外面 我按下了我的
mouse the scroll wheel so if we adjust
用鼠标滚动滚轮 这样如果我们调整
that we see where it's changing just the
我们看到了它正在改变的地方
darkness of that yellow but it's keeping
那黄色的黑暗 但它保持着
it the same
它是一样的
Hieu if we double-click it'll reset to
Hieu如果我们双击它 它将重置为
zero we can also adjust the saturation
零我们还可以调整饱和度
so our mark is still there that black
所以我们的目标仍然是那个黑色的
line is still there we can give it less
线还在那里 我们可以给它更少
if we go down it's less saturation all
如果我们往下走 饱和度就会降低
the way to pretty close we can go to
接近的方法是我们可以去
black and white I think or we can give
黑白的 我想或者我们可以给
it more saturation all the way up to
一路走到现在更饱和了
really kind of unrealistic looking
看起来真的很不现实
unnatural looking double-click brings
看起来不自然的双击带来了
that back into normal and the hue is
回到正常状态 色调是
kind of the fun one so the hue is what
有点有趣 所以色调是什么
lets us take it where it's at right now
让我们把它放在现在的位置上
is sort of this yellowish greenish color
是一种黄绿色
and if we move it up we can move it into
如果我们把它往上移 我们就能把它移到
a more green or more blue I'm getting my
一个更绿或更蓝的我得到了我的
mouse out of the way because it has this
鼠标让开 因为它有这个
yellow thing around it so you can't see
它周围有黄色的东西 所以你看不见
very well with it but if we drag it down
很好 但如果我们把它拖下去
it'll go into the blues or purpley we
它将进入忧郁或紫色的我们
get really down into those blues and if
真正沉浸在忧郁中 如果
we bring it up we can get it into also
我们把它提出来 我们也能把它弄进去
well blues it's sort of it sort of loops
嗯 布鲁斯 这是一种循环
over again so once you get to the very
再来一遍 一旦你到了非常
top it loops over back to the bottom but
它在顶部循环回到底部 但
we can get some greens in there so we
我们可以在那里买些蔬菜 这样我们就可以
can keep those greens you see it looks a
可以保持那些绿色 你看 它看起来
little bit maybe not so realistic so we
可能有一点不太现实 所以我们
can take down the saturation now so we
现在可以降低饱和度 所以我们
can bring down the saturation a little
可以把饱和度降低一点
bit or bring down the lightness a little
稍微把亮度调低一点
bit of those so that looks more like
一些 所以看起来更像
kind of more like paint and then we can
更像是画 然后我们就可以
do the same thing we can create another
做同样的事情 我们可以创造另一个
instance of this this is something we
这个例子这是我们的东西
haven't really learned yet I don't think
我还没有真正学会 我不认为
if we click this icon here and go to new
如果我们点击此处的图标并转到新建
instance now we have a color zones one
实例现在我们有了一个颜色区域
so we have color zones
所以我们有颜色区域
where to go we have covers owns that we
何去何从我们有自己的掩护 我们
just did then we have color zones one so
刚刚做了 然后我们有一个色区 所以
under cover zones one we can do the same
在第一区的掩护下 我们可以做同样的事情
thing to this other side we select sort
在另一边 我们选择排序
of the colors that those are at and then
它们的颜色 然后
we can do the same thing change the hue
我们可以做同样的事情 改变色调
of just those colors and so we can make
这些颜色 这样我们就可以
those from sort of more purple like and
那些来自更紫色的 像和
change the saturation of those and the
改变这些的饱和度和
lightness of those as well if we want to
如果我们想的话 这些也是轻盈的
darker or lighter you will go darker on
无论是深色还是浅色 你都会变得更暗
that so we've really kind of made we've
所以我们真的做出了我们的
changed the way this looks without
改变了这件事的外观
affecting the whites that's kind of the
影响白人 这是一种
problem a lot of times when you're
很多时候 当你在
trying to change the color of something
试图改变某物的颜色
you might go to grab this even my color
你可以去拿这个甚至是我的颜色
balance is gonna adjust the colors of
平衡将会调整颜色
the back of everything so the whites
所有东西的背面 所以白人
gets kind of thrown off a little bit
变得有点失控
color correction here is one that's a
这里的色彩校正是一种
really good thing but it it's good when
真的很好 但它是好的时候
you don't have a lot of whites for when
你不会有太多的白葡萄酒
you're okay adjusting your white balance
你可以调整你的白平衡
because it changes the way your whites
因为它改变了你的白人
look well the way we've done it we were
看看我们曾经做过的事
able to adjust these colors using the
能够使用调整这些颜色
color zones without affecting any other
不影响任何其他颜色区域
colors let's look at one more example
颜色：让我们再看一个例子
since this is a super fun and super
因为这是一个超级有趣和超级的
powerful tool here's a car that looks
强大的工具这是一辆看起来像是
pretty cool but we see I've adjusted a
很酷 但我们看到我已经调整了一个
little bit in the background there this
这是背景中的一点
is what the original looked like so it
是原版的样子所以它
was a blue car and then after the using
是一辆蓝色的车 然后在使用了
well I use color zones and zones on it
嗯 我在上面用了颜色区域和区域
to give us some more kind of contrast
给我们更多的对比
but so we can just go down to just that
但我们可以继续下去 就这样
base curve again compress history stack
基础曲线再次压缩历史堆栈
and we'll grab not color correction
我们会抓取而不是色彩校正
because color correction we know what
因为色彩校正我们知道
that does is make it look it adjusts
这确实让它看起来像是在调整
everything so we don't do color
所有的东西 所以我们不做颜色
correction we do color zones and the
更正我们做的颜色区域和
color is own we just find those blues we
颜色是我们自己的 我们只是找到那些蓝色 我们
can even just click in here and just
甚至只需点击此处即可
eyeball it without having to get the
看着它 而不需要得到
color picker and we can make them make
颜色选择器 我们可以让他们
it a lighter blue color we can go to the
它是一种浅蓝色的 我们可以去
hue and make it a different color
给它上色 让它变成不同的颜色
altogether we can make it more green we
总之 我们可以让它变得更加绿色 我们
can kind of bring that over and make it
能不能把它带过来 让它
more of a purple and without affecting
更多的是紫色 不影响
the brick and the rest of the building
砖块和建筑物的其余部分
so really really cool stuff that we can
所以非常非常酷的东西 我们可以
do here and we didn't have to do any
在这里做 我们不需要做任何
masking at all to achieve this look so
为了达到这样的效果 完全遮盖住了
it's really cool and we could do the
这真的很酷 我们可以做
same thing with the bricks if we want to
如果我们想的话砖也是一样的
do we could grab the color picker select
我们可以拿到颜色选择器吗？
the bricks the bricks are over here so
砖块砖块在这里 所以
we could change the color of the
我们可以改变颜色
building
建房
give it more you know have it look a
给它更多你知道的让它看起来像
little different color as well or we
颜色也略有不同 否则我们
could leave it the same color and change
可以让它保持相同的颜色和变化
the the darkness of it make it really a
它的黑暗使它成为一个真正的
darker building or make it look lighter
使建筑更暗或使其看起来更亮
but one more thing I wanted to mention
但还有一件事我想提一下
about this these zones do have these
关于这个 这些区域确实有这些
little triangles here at the bottom so
底部的小三角形 所以
if we want to let's bring that back kind
如果我们想把它带回来
of how it was this one with the car if
这辆车是怎么回事如果
we find that zone that that's in we can
我们找到了我们能找到的那个区域
adjust these triangles and get a little
调整这些三角形 得到一点
bit more accurate kind of makes this
稍微准确一点就能让这一点
more sharp and more pronounced so see
更尖锐 更明显 所以请看
what that's doing as we click these
当我们点击这些按钮时 它在做什么
triangles it sort of makes that
它的三角形就像是
selection area a little bit different
选择区域略有不同
but these triangles correspond with node
但这些三角形与节点相对应
with these circles the triangles
有了这些圆圈 就有了三角形
one with these circle nodes so if ever
一个有这些圆形节点的 所以如果有的话
there's a like if we want to select in
如果我们想要选择
between these two there's a circle here
在这两者之间有一个圆圈
and a circle here if you want to select
如果要选择 请在此处加上一个圆圈
in between the two bring one of these
在两者之间带来了一个这样的东西
over to that point and that's that
在这一点上 就是这样
I think this world will do it now in the
我认为这个世界现在就会这么做
there's another module called just
还有另一个模块叫Just
what's it called zones any but let's
它叫什么区域 除了让我们
find that zone system so the zone system
找到那个区域系统 这样区域系统
you can have some control over this too
你也可以对此进行一些控制
but just without colors anyway I just
但无论如何 我只是没有颜色
want to throw it out there appreciate
想把它扔到外面去欣赏
you guys watching leave your questions
你们在看的人留下你们的问题
and comments below if you have any and
下面的评论 如果你有
I'll catch you in the next video
下一段视频里我们会看到